checkatrade.com 2019-04-18

# Checkatrade: Checkatrade privacy notice

Here at Checkatrade we know how important it is to keep your personal data safe, that’s why we’re committed to making sure that you receive the service you’d expect and that your privacy is protected every step of the way. 

Checkatrade is a trading name of Vetted Ltd and is part of the HomeServe Group. Vetted Ltd is the data controller. For more information on the HomeServe Group and how we use your personal data, please see our group privacy notice [here](https://www.homeserve.com/uk/about/privacy-policy). 

In this notice you’ll discover exactly what information we collect from you and how we then use this to deliver our services, as well as your rights. It might not be something you’re interested in, but it’s really important you have a read and of course, let us know if you have any questions. 

  * ## So, how do we use your information?

### If you are a Trader

When you join Checkatrade we’ll collect some of your personal details so that we can make sure you have everything you need to make the most of our services. Please rest assured that we’ll only use this information for administering your membership and to support you while you’re a member. 

Examples of the types of personal information we usually collect are: 

    * Name
    * Address
    * Telephone number (including mobile)
    * Email address
    * Date of birth
    * Payment details (Direct Debit, credit/debit card number)
    * Trade category

It is important to note that in order to become a Checkatrade member that you will also have to pass our independent checks which include sharing data with Trading Standards. The information we collect as part of your membership application will be used to carry out these checks. 

None of the information you provide will ever be used for any other purpose without your permission. If any of the data is missing from the application form or is incorrect, we may not be able to process your application. 

### Using Checktrade

If you are visiting our website then we will collect information about your computer which includes your I.P. address. We collect this information as it allows us to monitor how effective our website is and how easily it is for you to get around. We also use Cookies, which are little bits of code that attach to your web browser and again help us to see how the site is working. You can read more about cookies and how to manage them [here](https://www.checkatrade.com/About/Cookies.aspx). 

We monitor calls made to Traders via Checkatrade.com so that we can better understand the service provided by our members. If you call a Trader using a telephone number listed on our website we will store a record of your telephone number and we may contact you for market research purposes and to find out more about your experience with our members. 

When you use a Checkatrade member they will provide you with a feedback form to fill in and return to us. We use the feedback forms to collect information about our members so that we can make sure they are providing the best service. In order to validate feedback we ask you for the following personal information: 

    * Name
    * Address
    * Telephone number
    * Email address
    * Signature

We will only ever use your personal information to contact you about your review and to make sure it is genuine. If you have given your consent, we will also use your details to tell you about other products and services that we think may be of interest to you. We will never sell or share your details with third parties for marketing purposes. 

If you are happy to provide feedback on the work that has been carried out we will publish your review on the website although we will never display your full details and you can request to have your review removed at any time. 

Any feedback submitted to us will be provided to the relevant member if they request it and they can use it on other platforms or marketing materials which are not owned or controlled by Checkatrade. We will only ever share your feedback, not your personal details. 

  * ## Using information provided by third parties

We use data from third parties and publicly available sources such as Companies House, Experian, the edited electoral roll or the deceased preference service. Using this data helps us to ensure that our records are accurate and up to date by filling in any gaps on an address or clarifying vanity addresses and house numbers. It also allows us to remove anyone from our mailings that has passed away. 

We also use data for marketing purposes. Any data we use in this way is thoroughly checked by both the supplier and our own internal teams to ensure that the correct marketing permissions are in place and that the data is being used fairly. 

  * ## Keeping and storing your data

If you’re a current or past member, we’ll keep a copy of your personal details for no longer than 6 years, from the time your active membership with us ends. Holding on to data allows us to keep accurate records for tax purposes and to handle any future complaints. 

If you have submitted feedback on a member, we will keep a record of your personal information for as long as the review remains on the website. Keeping a record of all reviews allows us to monitor feedback and combat fraudulent activity. 

Some of the data that we collect may be transferred to and stored at a destination outside the European Economic Area ('EEA'). We take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated in accordance with this privacy notice and applicable privacy laws. 

  * ## Sharing your data with third parties

We respect your privacy and that’s why we don’t share or sell your data to any third parties. However, on occasion and in addition to the above, we will pass your information to a limited number of third parties for the following reasons: 

    * To enable carefully selected partners to provide you with member benefits such as discounted rates on materials, vehicles or tools and Public Liability Insurance
    * To allow us to carry out certain background checks including sharing data with local Trading Standards offices
    * To deliver the services you’ve asked for including passing details to payment providers
    * For legal or regulatory purposes including fraud prevention
    * If we buy or sell any business or company assets

  * ## We’ll always keep you in the loop

Whenever we collect your personal information we’ll give you the opportunity to let us know how you’d like us to get in touch in the future. We promise not to inundate you with marketing messages but we also understand if you’d prefer not to receive anything from us. 

If you’ve asked us to send you marketing material, you can change your mind at any time by contacting us using the details in the Contact Us section. You’ll also find an unsubscribe link at the bottom of every marketing email we send to you. 

### Service messages

If you’re a member and you’ve given us an email address you may receive messages related to the management of your membership, which include payment and renewal documents. If you’d prefer not to receive these messages in this way, just let us know and we’ll be happy to provide them in paper form instead. 

  * ## Your rights matter

If you’d like to see the personal information that we hold about you, you can request a copy any time. If you find that this information is incorrect you can ask for it to be updated. Or, if you believe the information is being processed without a legal basis, you can ask us to stop or request that it’s deleted from our systems. 

To action any of the above, send an email to: [contact@checkatrade.com](mailto:contact@checkatrade.com) or alternatively you can write to us at: 

Data Protection Officer  
Checkatrade Head Office  
5 - 6 Sherrington Mews, Ellis Square,  
Selsey,  
West Sussex,  
PO20 0FJ

We won’t ever charge you for a copy of your personal data but we may ask you for proof of your identity before we disclose any information. Once we’ve seen this, we’ll send you a copy of the personal data we hold within 30 days. In addition, if you decide to move away from us for any reason, you can also request for your personal data to be transferred to a new provider on your behalf. 

  * ## Contact us

### Data Controller

Vetted Ltd  
Checkatrade Head Office  
5 - 6 Sherrington Mews, Ellis Square,  
Selsey,  
West Sussex,  
PO20 0FJ

Tel: [0333 0146 190](tel:03330146190)

### Data Protection Officer

Data Protection Officer  
Legal Services  
HomeServe PLC  
Cable Drive  
Walsall  
WS2 7BN

Tel: [01922 659700](tel:01922659700)  
Email: [Privacy@homeserve.com](mailto:Privacy@homeserve.com)

  * ## Got any worries?

If, at any time, you feel that we haven’t processed your data fairly or you’re not satisfied with how we’ve handled your personal information, you can contact the Information Commissioners Office, who will look into this for you. For full details about how to share any concerns you may have, visit [ico.org.uk/make-a-complaint/](https://ico.org.uk/make-a-complaint/)

  * ## Updates

This notice will be updated from time to time and we recommend that you check back regularly but we will notify you of any changes through our website. The version number and date released will always be listed below:

Version number: 1.2

Date released: January 2019
